Guide to the Barry Silverstein Collection of Direct Marketing Materials, 1871-1967 and undated RL.11273
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Barry Silverstein Collection of Direct Marketing Materials
1871-1965 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Silverstein, Barry, 1948-
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
RL.11273
6.0 Linear Feet
Direct marketing executive who worked at Xerox and Epsilon before founding Directech I eMerge in 1983.
Arrangement
Organized into two series: Clippings File; and Mounted Advertisements.
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The Barry Silverstein Collection of Direct Marketing Materials were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 2016.
Related Materials
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections: Lester Wunderman papers; Wunderman Archives; Arlie Slabaugh Collection of Direct Marketing Materials.
Collection Overview
Consists primarily of clippings, brochures and print advertisements relating to companies selling directly to consumers. Periodicals include American Magazine, Harper's Monthly, Hearth and Home, Liberty, McCall's and Youth's Companion. Companies represented include Aetna, Alexander Hamilton Institute, Bristol-Myers, Brunswick, Burroughs, Corn Products Sales (Karo), Gold Medal, Jergens and Sears. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Direct marketing; Advertising, Direct marketing; Direct marketing -- History; Advertising, Direct-mail -- History; Advertising copy -- United States; John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
- Clippings File, 1871-1965; 1
  - American Magazine, 1917-1938; 10 folders (Box 1)
  - Century Illustrated Monthly Magazine, 1887 (Box 1)
  - Chautauquan, 1909 (Box 1)
  - Country Gentleman, 1953 (Box 1)
  - Demorest's Family Magazine, 1893-1897; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Everybody's Magazine, 1900 (Box 1)
  - Family Circle, 1950, 1964; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Good Housekeeping Sandwich Manual, 1951 (Box 1)
  - Harper's Magazine, 1871-1903; 7 folders (Box 1)
  - Household, 1952-1955; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Independent, 1917-1918; 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Independent, 1927 (Box 2)
  - Ladies' World, 1900 (Box 2)
  - Liberty, 1936-1946; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Literary Digest, 1919, 1925; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Mayflower, 1891 (Box 2)
  - Mother and Babe, 1893 (Box 2)
  - Newsweek, 1933, 1936; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Pall Mall, 1895 (Box 2)
  - Secrets, 1949 (Box 2)
  - Time, 1927-1929; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - Unknown, 1936-1965; 5 folders (Box 2)
  - Yankee, 1958, 1966; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - A. Burdette Smith, 1880s (Box 3)
  - Collier's, 1938 (Box 3)
  - Country Gentleman, 1917 (Box 3)
  - Esquire, 1936 (Box 3)
  - Farmer's Wife, 1915 (Box 3)
  - Hearth and Home, 1919-1930; 11 folders (Box 3)
  - Life, 1965 (Box 4)
  - Look, 1939 (Box 4)
  - McCall's, 1927-1958; 6 folders (Box 4)
  - Needlecraft, 1923 (Box 4)
  - New York Woman, 1936-1937; 2 folders (Box 4)
  - People's Home Journal, 1900-1920; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Pictorial Review, 1928 (Box 4)
  - Priscilla, 1913 (Box 4)
  - Unknown, 1952-1965; 3 folders (Box 4)
  - Woman's Home Companion, 1944 (Box 4)
  - Woman's World, 1920 (Box 4)
  - Youth's Companion, 1891-1901; 4 folders (Box 4)
- Mounted Advertisements, 1914-1965 and undated; 2
  - A.C. Gilbert (Erector Set), 1925 (Box 5)
  - Aetna Life Insurance, 1917 (Box 5)
  - Alexander Hamilton Institute, 1917-1921 (Box 5)
  - American Crayon Company, 1929 (Box 5)
  - American Institute of Business Psychology, 1918 (Box 5)
  - Book League of America, undated (Box 5)
  - Brunswick-Balke-Collender (Billiard tables), 1914 (Box 5)
  - Buescher Band Instruments, 1928 (Box 5)
  - Burroughs Adding Machine, undated (Box 5)
  - Californians Inc., undated (Box 5)
  - Federal Schools (Art instruction), 1928 (Box 5)
  - G.P. Putnam's Sons (Book of Opportunity), undated (Box 6)
  - Georgia Hughes (Kotex), 1950 (Box 6)
  - Gold Medal Foods (Babe Ruth's Autographed Moviebook), 1933 (Box 6)
  - Hanovia Chemical (Alpine sun lamp), 1929 (Box 6)
  - International Correspondence Schools, circa 1923 (Box 6)
  - Iroquois Electric Refrigeration Company, undated (Box 6)
  - J&P Coats (Spool Cotton Co.), undated (Box 6)
  - Karo Syrup (Corn Products Sales Company), 1956 and undated (Box 6)
  - LaSalle Extension University, undated (Box 6)
  - Liberty Mutual, 1936 (Box 6)
  - Martins-David (Minicam camera), undated (Box 6)
  - Ovaltine, 1928 (Box 6)
  - P.F. Collier & Son (Dr. Eliot's Five Foot Shelf of Books), undated (Box 6)
  - P.F. Collier & Son (Dr. Eliot's Five Foot Shelf of Books), 1928 (Box 7)
  - Paragon Institute Home Study Department, 1917 (Box 7)
  - Perfect Photo Club, undated (Box 7)
  - Physical Culture Hotel, undated (Box 7)
  - Pullman Company contest, 1939 (Box 7)
  - Royal Baking Powder, undated (Box 7)
  - Sears, Roebuck and Co. (Book of 100 Wonders), undated (Box 7)
  - Sears, Roebuck and Co. (catalog), undated (Box 7)
  - Simon and Schuster (The Secrets of Keeping Fit), 1936 (Box 7)
  - Typewriter Emporium (Underwood), undated (Box 7)
  - United Mutual Fire Insurance, 1936 (Box 7)
  - University Research (Lockerbie edition works of James Whitcomb Riley), circa 1919 (Box 7)
  - Walter J. Black (Complete Short Stories of Maupassant), 1928 (Box 7)
  - Wm. H. Wise (The Story of the Bible), 1939 (Box 7)
  - Acousticon (hearing aids), undated (Box 8)
  - Americana Encyclopedia, 1956 (Box 8)
  - Andrew Jergens (Woodbury), 1927 (Box 8)
  - Auto Knitter Hosiery, 1920 (Box 8)
  - B.F. Goodrich (Zippers), 1927 (Box 8)
  - Big 4 Grocery (Teaspoon offer), undated (Box 8)
  - Book of the Month Club, 1939 (Box 8)
  - Bristol-Myers (Ipana), 1927 (Box 8)
  - Brooks Appliance (Rupture appliance), undated (Box 8)
  - Buffalo Specialty (Liquid Veneer), 1916 (Box 8)
  - California Fruit Growers Exchange (Sunkist), 1926 (Box 8)
  - Canadian Government Travel Bureau, circa 1956 (Box 8)
  - Doubleday One Dollar Book Club, undated (Box 8)
  - E. Frederick's (Tru-Curl Permanent), undated (Box 8)
  - Edison Storage Battery, undated (Box 8)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, undated (Box 9)
  - Great Books of the Western World, undated (Box 9)
  - Hartman Furniture and Carpet, 1920 (Box 9)
  - Hawaiian Pineapple Company, 1927 (Box 9)
  - Hoosier Manufacturing (kitchen cabinets), undated (Box 9)
  - Jell-O, 1927 (Box 9)
  - Kalamazoo Stove, 1920 (Box 9)
  - Karo Syrup (Corn Products Sales Company), 1919 (Box 9)
  - L. Fish Furniture Company, circa 1918 (Box 9)
  - Longines Symphonette Recording Society, 1965 (Box 9)
  - Loose-Wiles Biscuit Company (Sunshine brand), undated (Box 9)
  - McKeeson Robbins (Calox tooth powder), 1937 (Box 9)
  - Miscellaneous (Mentholatum, Haverford Bicycle, Allen's Foot-Ease, Mead Cycle, Green Meadow Club), 1920 (Box 9)
  - Montgomery Ward, 1923 (Box 9)
  - Montgomery Ward, 1924 (Box 10)
  - MONY (Mutual of New York), 1964 (Box 10)
  - New Idea Spreader (farm machinery), undated (Box 10)
  - Pepsodent, 1920 (Box 10)
  - Phillies Cheroot (cigars), 1965 (Box 10)
  - Rexall, 1965 (Box 10)
  - Sonotone (hearing aid), undated (Box 10)
  - Time-Life Books, circa 1960s (Box 10)
  - U.S. Playing Card Company, 1928 (Box 10)